Mertz mss., 1902-2019 LMC 2914
Lilly Library
- Barbara Michaels
  - Vanish With the Rose
    - Second draft - annotated typescript, 1990; 3 Folders (Box 46, Folder 12-14)
    - Revised draft - typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 46, Folder 15-17)
    - Setter's proof - annotated typescript (folder 1), 1992? (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Setter's proof - annotated typescript (folders 2-3), 1992?; 2 Folders (Box 47, Folder 1-2)
    - Draft - typescript, undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 47, Folder 4-5)
    - Cover proof, undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Reviews and publicity, undated (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Notes and research materials, undated (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Houses of Stone
    - First draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 47, Folder 9-10)
    - Second draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 47, Folder 11-13)
    - Draft - annotated typescript, undated; 4 Folders (Box 47, Folder 14-17)
    - Revised draft - typescript (folders 1-2), undated; 2 Folders (Box 47, Folder 18-19)
    - Revised draft - typescript (folders 3-4), undated; 2 Folders (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
    - Draft - annotated typescript, undated; 4 Folders (Box 48, Folder 3-6)
    - Plot outline, notes, and research materials, 1990-1991? (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1993-1994? (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - The Dancing Floor
    - Final draft - typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 48, Folder 9-11)
    - Second draft - typescript, undated (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - First draft - typescript, undated (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Author's copy, 27 August 1996; 3 Folders (Box 48, Folder 14-16)
    - Galleys - typescript (folders 1-2), 1996; 2 Folders (Box 48, Folder 17-18)
    - Galleys - typescript (folder 3), 1996 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 49, Folder 2-4)
    - Foul matter, 1996; 2 Folders (Box 49, Folder 5-6)
    - Page proofs, 10 October 1996; 2 Folders (Box 49, Folder 7-8)
    - Abridged audiobook script, 19 November 1996 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Revised draft - annotated typescript, undated; 3 Folders (Box 49, Folder 10-12)
    - Draft - typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 49, Folder 13-14)
    - Plot outlines, notes, and research materials, 1982-1995; 2 Folders (Box 49, Folder 15-16)
    - Reviews and publicity, 1996-1997 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Cover proofs, undated (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Other Worlds
    - Foul matter, 18 February 1999; 2 Folders (Box 49, Folder 19-20)
    - Draft - typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
    - Draft - typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 50, Folder 3-4)
    - Page proofs, 11 September 1998; 2 Folders (Box 50, Folder 5-6)
    - Draft - typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 50, Folder 7-8)
    - Revised draft - annotated typescript, undated; 2 Folders (Box 50, Folder 9-10)
    - Abridged audiobook script, 23 September 1998 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - "The Bell Witch" - typescript, undated (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - "The Bell Witch" - typescript, April 1997 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - "The Phelps Case" - research materials, notes, and draft, 1997?; 2 Folders (Box 50, Folder 14-15)
    - Cover proofs, undated (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - "Bell Witch" - notes and research materials, undated; 3 Folders (Box 50, Folder 17-19)
    - Review, 1999 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Reissues - publishing correspondence, 2005-2007 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - "Greyhaven Saga" - notebook, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Introduction to Mistress of Shadows, undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Welcome Barbara Michaels" banner (Box 197)
  - Possible titles, undated (Box 191, Folder 22)
- Correspondence
  - Literary
    - HarperCollins, 1994-2011; 4 Folders (Box 51, Folder 3-6)
    - HarperCollins, 2006-2009; 2 Folders (Box 194, Folders 17-18)
    - Constable-Robinson, 1999-2005; 2 Folders (Box 51, Folder 7-8)
    - Constable-Robinson, 2006-2007 (Box 194, Folder 16)
    - Avon, 1997-2008; 8 Folders (Box 51, Folder 9-16)
    - Warner, 1995-1997; 2 Folders (Box 51, Folder 17-18)
    - 1976 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - 1984 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 1985, 5 Folders (Box 52, Folder 2-6)
    - 1986 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - 1987, 3 Folders (Box 52, Folder 8-10)
    - 1990, 2 Folders (Box 52, Folder 11-12)
    - 1991, 4 Folders (Box 52, Folder 13-16)
    - 1992, 4 Folders (Box 52, Folder 17-20)
    - 1993, 2 Folders (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
    - 1994, 2 Folders (Box 53, Folder 3-4)
    - 1995, 2 Folders (Box 53, Folder 5-6)
    - 1996, 2 Folders (Box 53, Folder 7-8)
    - 1997, 2 Folders (Box 53, Folder 9-10)
    - 1998, 2 Folders (Box 53, Folder 11-12)
    - 1999, 2 Folders (Box 53, Folder 13-14)
    - 2000, 2 Folders (Box 53, Folder 15-16)
    - 2001, 2 Folders (Box 53, Folder 17-18)
    - 2002 (folder 1) (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - 2002 (folder 2) (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - 2003 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - 2004, 2 Folders (Box 54, Folder 3-4)
    - 2005 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - 2006 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - 2007 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - 2008 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - 2009 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - 2010 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - 2012-2013 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Personal
    - Friends - Egypt, 1997; 2 Folders (Box 54, Folder 12-13)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2000; 3 Folders (Box 54, Folder 14-16)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2001; 3 Folders (Box 54, Folder 17-19)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2002; 3 Folders (Box 55, Folder 1-3)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2003; 3 Folders (Box 55, Folder 4-6)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2004; 2 Folders (Box 55, Folder 7-8)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2005; 3 Folders (Box 55, Folder 9-11)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2006; 2 Folders (Box 55, Folder 12-13)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2007; 2 Folders (Box 55, Folder 14-15)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2008; 2 Folders (Box 55, Folder 16-17)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2009; 3 Folders (Box 55, Folder 18-20)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2010 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Friends - Egypt, 2011; 3 Folders (Box 195, Folder 1-3)
    - "KV63", 2005-2006; 3 Folders (Box 56, Folder 2-4)
    - Sarah Caudwell's memorial and "beano", 2000 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - 85th birthday cards, 2012; 5 Folders (Box 56, Folder 6-10)
    - "Old letters from writers", 1979-1986 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Cat postcards (folders 1-6), undated; 6 Folders (Box 56, Folder 12-17)
      Some cards include correspondence to Mertz
    - Cat postcards (folders 7-8), undated; 2 Folders (Box 57, Folder 1-2)
    - 80th birthday cards, 2007 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - 1987, 4 Folders (Box 57, Folder 4-7)
    - 1988, 3 Folders (Box 57, Folder 8-10)
    - 1989, 4 Folders (Box 57, Folder 11-14)
    - 1990 (folders 1-3), 3 Folders (Box 57, Folder 15-17)
    - 1990 (folders 4-6), 3 Folders (Box 58, Folder 1-3)
    - 1991, 6 Folders (Box 58, Folder 4-9)
    - 1992, 6 Folders (Box 58, Folder 10-15)
    - 1993 (folders 1-2), 2 Folders (Box 58, Folder 16-17)
    - 1993 (folders 3-5), 3 Folders (Box 59, Folder 1-3)
    - 1994, 7 Folders (Box 59, Folder 4-10)
    - 1995 (folders 1-6), 6 Folders (Box 59, Folder 11-16)
    - 1995 (folders 7-8), 2 Folders (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
    - 1996, 8 Folders (Box 60, Folder 3-10)
    - 1997, 4 Folders (Box 60, Folder 11-14)
    - 1998, 3 Folders (Box 60, Folder 15-17)
    - 1999 (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - 2000, 4 Folders (Box 61, Folder 1-4)
    - 2001, 4 Folders (Box 61, Folder 5-8)
    - 2002, 4 Folders (Box 61, Folder 9-12)
    - 2003, 3 Folders (Box 61, Folder 13-15)
    - 2004 (folder 1) (Box 61, Folder 16)
    - 2004 (folders 2-4), 3 Folders (Box 62, Folder 1-3)
    - 2005, 4 Folders (Box 62, Folder 4-7)
    - 2006, 4 Folders (Box 62, Folder 8-11)
    - 2007, 4 Folders (Box 62, Folder 12-15)
    - 2008 (folders 1-3), 3 Folders (Box 62, Folder 16-18)
    - 2008 (folders 4-6), 3 Folders (Box 63, Folder 1-3)
    - 2009, 6 Folders (Box 63, Folder 4-9)
    - 2010, 6 Folders (Box 63, Folder 10-15)
    - 2011 (folders 1-3), 3 Folders (Box 63, Folder 16-18)
    - 2011 (folder 4) (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - 2011 (folders 5-6), 2 Folders (Box 194, Folders 20-21)
    - 2012, 2 Folders (Box 64, Folder 2, Box 194, Folder 19)
    - Undated (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Phyllis Whitney, 1979 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Phyllis Whitney, 1980-1989; 2 Folders (Box 64, Folder 5-6)
    - Phyllis Whitney, 1990-1999; 2 Folders (Box 64, Folder 7-8)
    - Phyllis Whitney, 2000-2006 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Joan Hess, 1988-1989 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Joan Hess, 1990-1994; 2 Folders (Box 64, Folder 11-12)
    - Joan Hess, 1995-1999; 3 Folders (Box 64, Folder 13-15)
    - Joan Hess, 2000-2009; 2 Folders (Box 64, Folder 16-17)
    - Joan Hess, 2010-2011 (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - Joan Hess - "Sheep Wars", 1992-1993? (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - 75th birthday cards (folders 1-2), 2002; 2 Folders (Box 64, Folder 20-21)
    - 75th birthday cards (folder 3), 2002 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Memorial for Alexandra "Sandy" Ripley, 2004 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Condolences and letters regarding death of Grace and Earl Gross, 1978-1979 (Box 194, Folder 15)
    - Dennis Forbes, 1993-1997 (Box 195, Folder 4)
      Includes negatives, slides, and photos
  - Fanmail and Fandom
    - 1967, 2 Folders (Box 65, Folder 3-4)
    - 1975 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - 1976 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - 1977 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - 1978 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - 1979 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - 1980, 2 Folders (Box 65, Folder 10-11)
    - 1982 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - 1983, 2 Folders (Box 65, Folder 13-14)
    - 1984 (Box 65, Folder 15)
    - 1985 (Box 65, Folder 16)
    - 1986, 2 Folders (Box 65, Folder 17-18)
    - 1987, 2 Folders (Box 65, Folder 19-20)
    - 1988, 2 Folders (Box 65, Folder 21-22)
    - 1989, 2 Folders (Box 65, Folder 23-24)
    - 1990, 3 Folders (Box 66, Folder 1-3)
    - 1991, 2 Folders (Box 66, Folder 4-5)
    - 1992, 5 Folders (Box 66, Folder 6-10)
    - 1993, 6 Folders (Box 66, Folder 11-16)
    - 1994 (folder 1) (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - 1994 (folders 2-7), 6 Folders (Box 67, Folder 1-6)
    - 1995, 4 Folders (Box 67, Folder 7-10)
    - 1996, 6 Folders (Box 67, Folder 11-16)
    - 1997 (folder 1) (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - 1997 (folders 2-5), 4 Folders (Box 68, Folder 1-4)
    - 1998, 6 Folders (Box 68, Folder 5-10)
    - 1999, 8 Folders (Box 68, Folder 11-18)
    - 2000, 11 Folders (Box 69, Folder 1-11)
    - 2001 (folders 1-6), 6 Folders (Box 69, Folder 12-17)
    - 2001 (folders 7-9), 3 Folders (Box 70, Folder 1-3)
    - 2002, 10 Folders (Box 70, Folder 4-13)
    - 2003 (folders 1-4), 4 Folders (Box 70, Folder 14-17)
    - 2003 (folders 5-13), 9 Folders (Box 71, Folder 1-9)
    - 2004 (folders 1-7), 7 Folders (Box 71, Folder 10-16)
    - 2004 (folders 8-11), 4 Folders (Box 72, Folder 1-4)
    - 2005, 10 Folders (Box 72, Folder 5-14)
    - 2006 (folders 1-3), 3 Folders (Box 72, Folder 15-17)
    - 2006 (folders 4-11), 8 Folders (Box 73, Folder 1-8)
    - 2007 (folders 1-8), 8 Folders (Box 73, Folder 9-16)
    - 2007 (folder 9) (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - 2008, 12 Folders (Box 74, Folder 2-13)
    - 2009 (folders 1-3), 3 Folders (Box 74, Folder 14-16)
    - 2009 (folders 4-9), 6 Folders (Box 75, Folder 1-6)
    - 2010, 8 Folders (Box 75, Folder 7-14)
    - 2011 (folders 1-3), 3 Folders (Box 75, Folder 15-17)
    - 2011 (folders 4-6), 3 Folders (Box 76, Folder 1-3)
    - 2012, 3 Folders (Box 76, Folder 4-6)
    - Gothics, 1966-1969 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Gothics, 1970-1974; 3 Folders (Box 76, Folder 8-10)
    - Gothics, 1975-1979; 4 Folders (Box 76, Folder 11-14)
    - Gothics, 1980-1982; 2 Folders (Box 76, Folder 15-16)
    - "Egypt books" (folder 1), 1964-1969 (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - "Egypt books" (folders 2-4), 1964-1969; 3 Folders (Box 77, Folder 1-3)
    - "Egypt books", 1970-1974; 2 Folders (Box 77, Folder 4-5)
    - "Egypt books", 1975-1979 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - "Egypt books", 1980-1984 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - "Egypt books", 1985-1989 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - MPM
      - Used in #10, 1991 (Box 77, Folder 9)
      - Used in #18, 1994-1995 (Box 77, Folder 10)
      - Used in #20, 1995 (Box 77, Folder 11)
      - Used in #25, 1997 (Box 77, Folder 12)
      - Used in #26, 1997 (Box 77, Folder 13)
      - Used in #27, 1997-1998 (Box 77, Folder 14)
      - Used in #29, 1998 (Box 77, Folder 15)
      - Used in #30, 1997-1998 (Box 77, Folder 16)
      - Used in #31, 1998-1999; 3 Folders (Box 77, Folder 17-19)
      - Used in #34, 2000 (Box 77, Folder 20)
      - Used in #38, 2000-2001 (Box 77, Folder 21)
      - Used in #39, 2001-2002 (Box 77, Folder 22)
      - Used in #40, 2002 (Box 77, Folder 23)
      - Used in #47, 2005 (Box 77, Folder 24)
      - Used in #49, 2005-2006 (Box 77, Folder 25)
      - Used in #1, 3, 6, 18, 19, 1990-1995 (Box 77, Folder 26)
      - Used in #19, 20, 21, 22, 1995-1996 (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Used in "MPM 1992" (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - Used in "end of 95 MPM", 1995; 2 Folders (Box 78, Folder 3-4)
      - Used in "next MPM", 1993-1994 (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Mailing lists, undated (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Ideas, notes, and drafts, 1993-1996? (Box 78, Folder 7)
      - Issues, 1990-1996; 4 Folders (Box 78, Folder 8, Box 195, Folders 5-7)
      - "In the Parlor" tape sales, 1990-1991 (Box 78, Folder 9)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 1990 (Box 78, Folder 10)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 1991 (Box 78, Folder 11)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 1992; 4 Folders (Box 78, Folder 12-15)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 1993 (Box 78, Folder 16)
      - Subscriptions and address changes (folders 1-3), 1994; 3 Folders (Box 78, Folder 17-19)
      - Subscriptions and address changes (folders 4-9), 1994; 6 Folders (Box 79, Folder 1-6)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 1995; 2 Folders (Box 79, Folder 7-8)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 1996; 2 Folders (Box 79, Folder 9-10)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 1997 (Box 79, Folder 11)
      - Subscriptions and address changes (folders 1-6), 1998; 6 Folders (Box 79, Folder 12-17)
      - Subscriptions and address changes (folders 7-9), 1998; 3 Folders (Box 80, Folder 1-3)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 1999; 9 Folders (Box 80, Folder 4-12)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 2000; 3 Folders (Box 80, Folder 13-15)
      - Subscriptions and address changes (folders 1-2), 2001; 2 Folders (Box 80, Folder 16-17)
      - Subscriptions and address changes (folder 3), 2001 (Box 81, Folder 1)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 2002; 2 Folders (Box 81, Folder 2-3)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 2003; 2 Folders (Box 81, Folder 4-5)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 2004 (Box 81, Folder 6)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 2005; 9 Folders (Box 81, Folder 7-15)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 2006 (Box 81, Folder 16)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 2007 (Box 81, Folder 17)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 2008 (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - Subscriptions and address changes, 2009 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - FOEP (Friends of Elizabeth Peters)
      - Issues 1-13, 1983-1991 (Box 82, Folder 3)
      - Mailing lists, 1986-1988 (Box 82, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence (5 folders), 1985-1990; 5 Folders (Box 82, Folder 5-9)
      - "Entries in FOEP plot contest", undated (Box 194, Folder 14)
    - Fan questions from unknown event, undated (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Fan petition for new Vicky Bliss book, 2001 (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Fancasts for Amelia Peabody, 2009 (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - Website drafts (official and unofficial), 1995-2008; 2 Folders (Box 82, Folder 13-14)
    - Gifts from fans, 1993? (Box 82, Folder 15)
  - Business
    - 1978 (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - 1979, 2 Folders (Box 82, Folder 17-18)
    - 1980, 3 Folders (Box 82, Folder 19-21)
    - 1981, 2 Folders (Box 82, Folder 22-23)
    - 1982, 3 Folders (Box 83, Folder 1-3)
    - 1983, 3 Folders (Box 83, Folder 4-6)
    - 1984, 3 Folders (Box 83, Folder 7-9)
    - 1985 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - 1986, 5 Folders (Box 83, Folder 11-15)
    - 1987, 2 Folders (Box 83, Folder 16-17)
    - 1988 (folder 1) (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - 1988 (folders 2-5), 4 Folders (Box 84, Folder 1-4)
    - 1989, 6 Folders (Box 84, Folder 5-10)
    - 1990, 5 Folders (Box 84, Folder 11-15)
    - 1991 (Box 84, Folder 16)
    - 1992 (Box 84, Folder 17)
    - 1993 (Box 84, Folder 18)
    - 1994 (Box 84, Folder 19)
    - 1995 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - 1996 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - 1997, 2 Folders (Box 85, Folder 3-4)
    - 1998 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - 1999 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - 2000 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - 2001 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - 2003 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - 2004 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - 2006 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - 2007 (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - 2008 (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - 2009 (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - 2011 (Box 85, Folder 15)
- Other Writings
  - "Amelia's Real-Life Sisters" - drafts, undated (Box 85, Folder 16)
  - "Article on reviewers - never printed in Post" - correspondence and drafts, 1991 (Box 85, Folder 17)
  - "B + N?" - draft, 2001 (Box 85, Folder 18)
  - Book reviews - drafts and clippings, 1978-2000; 2 Folders (Box 85, Folder 19-20)
  - Certain Titles of the Egyptian Queens and their Bearing of the Hereditary Right to the Throne - bound dissertation, August 1952 (Box 85, Folder 21)
  - "Charlotte MacLeod for Bouchercon" - drafts, undated (Box 85, Folder 22)
  - Christmas Stalkings - "Liz Peters, P.I." - correspondence, drafts, publicity and pamphlet, 1990-2003 (Box 85, Folder 23)
  - "Cozy v. Hardboiled: Which is More Realistic?" - correspondence and draft, 1997 (Box 85, Folder 24)
  - "Egypt 2006" - draft (Box 192, Folder 29)
  - "Egyptian Diary" - drafts, 2000-2001 (Box 85, Folder 25)
  - Encyclopedia Americana - "Egypt, Ancient" - correspondence and drafts, 1971 (Box 85, Folder 26)
  - Encyclopaedia Brittanica - "Memphis" - correspondence and drafts, 1970-1997 (Box 85, Folder 27)
  - "Finding the Tomb of Tetisheri" - draft, undated (Box 85, Folder 28)
  - Forerunners of Amarna - bound dissertation, December 1950 (Box 85, Folder 29)
  - Forerunners of Amarna - bound typescript, 1950 (Box 193, Folder 6)
  - Foreword to Charlotte MacLeod's Grab Bag - correspondence and draft, 2001 (Box 85, Folder 30)
  - Foreword to Charlotte MacLeod's Resurrection Man - draft, undated (Box 85, Folder 31)
  - "How to Write the Supernatural Novel of Suspense" - The Writer, 1988 (Box 193, Folder 1)
  - "In the Attic" - drafts and Mystery Scene, undated (Box 85, Folder 32)
  - "It's All Part of the Deal" - draft, undated (Box 85, Folder 33)
  - Jefferson Encyclopedia (World Publishing Company) - "Egypt" - correspondence and drafts, 1969 (Box 85, Folder 34)
  - "The Lake Nasser Cruise/Cruising to the Rescued Treasures of Nubia" - correspondence, drafts and The Sophisticated Traveler, 1996 (Box 85, Folder 35)
  - Malice Domestic #1 - publicity, 1992 (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - "Malice Domestic" - correspondence and drafts, 1993 (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - "Mysteries are Serious Business" - drafts, undated (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - National Geographic - "Mysteries" - correspondence, notes and draft, 1978 (Box 193, Folder 7)
  - National Geographic - "Our World's Heritage" - correspondence and research, 1986 (Box 193, Folder 8)
  - National Geographic - "Ancient Mesopotamia and Egypt" - annotated film scripts, 1978 (Box 193, Folder 9)
  - National Geographic - "Pleasures of Life" - drafts and correspondence, 1978; 2 Folders (Box 193, Folders 10-11)
  - "Notes for an Egyptian novel I will never write" - notebook, undated (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Notes for unknown work about "Uncle Edgar", undated (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - "Peter Shandy" - drafts, undated (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - "Plotting the Gothic novel" - The Writer, 1980 (Box 193, Folder 4)
  - "Series Characters" - drafts and The Writer, 1994 (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - "Series Characters" - The Writer, 1994 (Box 192, Folder 31)
  - "Short, Fat and Handsome" - drafts and clippings, 1991 (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Sisters in Crime I - "The Locked Tomb Mystery" and "The Runaway" - drafts and publicity, 1989 (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - "Smithsonian talk - Gothic" - drafts, correspondence and research, 1982 (Box 192, Folder 28)
  - "Speech - Chicago" - drafts and notes, 1997 (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - "Speech - Cincinnati" - draft, undated (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - "Stakeout in Stockholm: Crime Writers' Congress" - draft and clippings, 1981 (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - "Talk, DC ARCE" - notes and research material, 1991 (Box 86, Folder 13)
  - "Talk at U. Penn Museum" - drafts, 1996-1997 (Box 86, Folder 15)
  - Tribute to Joan Hess - draft, undated (Box 86, Folder 16)
  - Tribute to Joan Hess - Mystery Scene, 2002 (Box 193, Folder 2)
  - Unpublished article on Amelia Peabody's clothing - notes and drafts, 1998 (Box 86, Folder 17)
  - "What's in a Pen Name?" - The Writer, 1982 (Box 193, Folder 5)
  - "Whither the Gothic?" - clipping, undated (Box 86, Folder 18)
  - "The Willing Suspension of Disbelief" - The Writer, 1974 (Box 193, Folder 3)
  - World Book Encyclopedia - "Ancient Civilization" and "Pyramid" - correspondence and drafts, 1966-1971 (Box 86, Folder 19)
  - "The Writing Life" - correspondence, drafts and response letter, 2001 (Box 86, Folder 20)
  - "Zahi Hawass" - correspondence and drafts, 2006 (Box 86, Folder 21)
  - "Zahi Hawass" - Time magazine, 9 May 2006 (Box 192, Folder 30)
  - Unidentified or incomplete drafts, undated (Box 86, Folder 22)
  - "Certain Titles of of the Egyptian Queens and their Bearing on the Hereditary Right to the Throne" - typescript, 1952 (Box 86, Folders 23-24)
- Publicity and Appearances
  - Invitations and Requests
    - Accepted, 1990-1994; 3 Folders (Box 86, Folder 1-3)
    - Accepted, 1995-1999; 2 Folders (Box 86, Folder 4-5)
    - Accepted, 2000-2004; 2 Folders (Box 86, Folder 6-7)
    - Accepted, 2005-2009 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Accepted, 2010-2011 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Ignored, 1990-1994 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Ignored, 1995-1999 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Ignored, 2000-2004 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Ignored, 2005-2011; 2 Folders (Box 87, Folder 2-3)
    - Declined, 1990-1994; 5 Folders (Box 87, Folder 4-8)
    - Declined, 1995-1999; 4 Folders (Box 87, Folder 9-12)
    - Declined, 2000-2004; 4 Folders (Box 87, Folder 13-16)
    - Declined (folder 1), 2005-2009 (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - Declined (folders 2-4), 2005-2009; 3 Folders (Box 88, Folder 1-3)
    - Declined, 2009 (Box 192, Folder 5)
    - Declined, 2010-2011 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Declined, 2012 (Box 192, Folder 6)
    - Declined - Massachusetts Museum, 1995 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Unknown response, 1990-2007 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1966-1979 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1982 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1983 (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1984 (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1987 (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1988 (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1990; 2 Folders (Box 88, Folder 14-15)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1991 (Box 88, Folder 16)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1992; 3 Folders (Box 88, Folder 17-19)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1993; 3 Folders (Box 88, Folder 20-21, Box 192, Folder 11)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1994 (Box 88, Folder 22)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1995 (Box 88, Folder 23)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1996; 2 Folders (Box 89, Folder 1-2)
  - Interviews, publicity, and appearance ephemera, 1997; 2 Folders (Box 89, Folder 3-4)